Sani Muhammad Jamil

Fullstack Software Developer

Abuja, Nigeria

+234 7035483237

portfolio.jamsanz.xyz

github.com/jamsanz

Summary

Strong software engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree focused on Computer Science. Skilled in Frontend and Back-End Web Development and Cross-platform mobile development with demonstrated history/working experience in the computer software industry.

Skills

HTML, CSS3, Javascript ES6, Typescript, React, Redux, Nextjs, React Native, Nodejs, Nestjs, Expressjs, Firebase, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, REST API(s), GraphQL, Bootstrap, Reactstrap, Material UI, Tailwind CSS, Java, Python, Git.

Work experience

Fullstack Software Developer

2021-04 - Till date

Wootlab Innovations

- Developed and maintained multiple applications using ReactJS, Redux, and Typescript to create a dynamic user experience with optimal performance.
- Used NextJS to build fast and optimized server-side rendered React applications, resulting in improved user experience and increased performance.
- Built cross-platform mobile applications using React Native and integrated with REST API(s) to access and manage data from the backend.
- Worked with NodeJS to build scalable and efficient server-side applications and integrated them with GraphQL and REST API(s) for optimized data retrieval and management.
- Implemented data storage solutions using both MySQL and MongoDB, ensuring data consistency and security across all applications.
- Utilized Redux to manage and maintain the state of applications, resulting in improved app functionality and user experience.
- Designed and implemented efficient data retrieval systems using GraphQL, resulting in reduced load times and improved data management.
- Maintained code quality and collaborated with the development team to ensure all applications were developed to meet the needs of clients and users.
- Contributed to the implementation of continuous integration and delivery processes using Git, GitHub, and Vercel to ensure the seamless delivery of updates and new features to users.

Web Developer - Intern

09-2018 - 12-2018

Fixable Systems

- Designed and developed an online helpdesk system for university students to lodge their complaints regarding difficulties they might be facing in the university using HTML, CSS, PHP, and MySQL.
- Designed and developed a restaurant management system for tracking inventories and sales.
- Setting up small offices (Switching & routing) Networking.
- Computer software(OS) and hardware repairs Maintenance
- Managed databases Database Administrator (MYSQL)
- Design and development of basic websites using HTML & CSS

Project Highlights

Nigerian Jubilee Fellowship Programme (NJFP) - https://njfp.ng
Sub-components: E-leaning, Monitoring & evaluation system, Applicants portal & Alumni platform
Technologies: React, Redux, Next, Typescript, Java (Springboot), MySQL

Role: Frontend developer.

 Mobile App iOS & Android for reporting electoral incidents (weWatch) https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.jamsanz.weWatch

Technologies: Typescript, React Native, NativeBase, Node (NestJs), MongoDB

Role: Fullstack developer

• Mobile App iOS & Android for property management (Ab-properties) -

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.jamsanz.abproperties

Technologies: Typescript, React Native, Redux, NativeBase, Node, MongoDB

Role: Fullstack developer

• Mobile App iOS & Android for Kaduna State PDP Agents (Election results)

https://expo.dev/@jamsanz/election-results?serviceType=classic&distribution=expo-go

Technologies: Typescript, React Native, Tailwindcss, Node (NestJs), MongoDB

Role: Fullstack developer

• Mobile App iOS & Android data collection (Data Collect)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.jamsanz.datacollect

Technologies: React Native, Redux, Google Places API, Google Autocomplete API

Role: Fullstack developer

• Al powered fraud prevention for fintechs and e-commerce in Africa (MayGuard) -

https://portal.mayguard.ai

Technologies: React, Next, Typescript, Material UI, Nodejs (Express), MongoDB (Mongoose)

Role: Frontend developer

• Fullstack Web Application for Wootlab Innovations - https://wootlab.ng

Technologies: React, Next, Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Nodejs (Express), MongoDB (Mongoose)

Role: Fullstack developer

• Uber Clone (Mobile App iOS & Android) - https://expo.dev/@jamsanz/uber-clone

Technologies: React Native, Redux, Google Places API, Google Autocomplete API

Role: Sole developer

• Mediaplus Consultancy - https://atmediaplus-consulatncy.org

Technologies: React, Next, Typescript, Node (Express), MongoDB (Mongoose)

Role: Sole developer

Education

Bachelor's Degree

2016-01 - 2020-07

Al-Qalam University

BSc. Computer Science Second class upper

4.4

Certifications

- GraphQL Associate Developer
- Javascript Certificate
- React + Redux Certificate
- CSS Certificate
- ¡Query Certificate
- MySQL Certificate
- PHP Certificate
- HTML Certificate
- Certificate in making businesses digital and global